<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content"><channel><title>Today I Learnt</title><description>Keeping track of one new thing I learn everyday</description><link>blog.ehudadler.com</link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 22:45:32 -0500</lastBuildDate><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 22:45:32 -0500</pubDate><ttl>250</ttl><atom:link href="blog.ehudadler.com/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><guid isPermaLink="true">blog.ehudadler.com/posts/orbit-area</guid><title>Janurary 16th 2020</title><description>The region between equally spaced moments in orbit always have the same area</description><link>blog.ehudadler.com/posts/orbit-area</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 22:09:00 -0500</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Janurary 16th 2020</h1><p>I am fortunate to be close with a few of the professors at my university. Recently one of them told me to watch a set of lectures known as the messengers lectures given by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Feynman">Richard Feynman</a>. Today I watched the first of these lectures (of which there are 7). The first lecture, titled "Law of Gravitation — An Example of Physical Law" can be found <a href="Law of Gravitation — An Example of Physical Law">on microsoft's website here</a> or on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j3mhkYbznBk&list=PLLzGzdSNup63lMYeOpU9Hax6MBsTjdDas">youtube here</a>.</p><p>So without further introduction.....</p><p>Today I learn't the following fact from Richard Feynman.</p><h3>Keplers 2nd Law</h3><p>If you look at the area formed when you draw a line between the sun, some planet and that same planet 3 weeks later on in its orbit, the area formed by the enclosing region will <strong>always</strong> be the same. This means, no matter where in the orbit the planet is, the region formed between the sun and it now and it in 3 weeks will always be the same, Furthermore, there is nothing special about 3 weeks. As long as you look at equal intervals of time, the area will be the same. This concept is depicted in the image below where 1 month in the chosen interval.</p><img width=25% src="https://eloisechen.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/kepler2law.jpg?w=1600&h=1200">


]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>