<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content"><channel><title>Today I Learned</title><description>Keeping track of one new thing I learn everyday</description><link>blog.ehudadler.com</link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 14:39:30 -0500</lastBuildDate><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 14:39:30 -0500</pubDate><ttl>250</ttl><atom:link href="blog.ehudadler.com/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><guid isPermaLink="true">blog.ehudadler.com/posts/rock-skipping</guid><title>Janurary 19th 2020</title><description>How to skip a rock</description><link>blog.ehudadler.com/posts/rock-skipping</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 14:34:00 -0500</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Janurary 19th 2020</h1><p>I enjoy watching educational youtube videos. Today I watched an old video (one I haven't seen though) from one of my favorite channels Mark Rober. He is an ex-Nasa Engineer and always makes interesting educational videos based in engineerings and physics.</p><p>This video, titled "<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M0_U1FHwACk">Rock Skip Robot- The Science of Perfect Rock Skipping</a>", allowed me to say the following thing,</p><p>Today I learned that the best way to skip a rock is to have the rock hit the water so that it forms a 20 degree angle</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">blog.ehudadler.com/posts/word-count</guid><title>Janurary 17th 2020</title><description>The average persons vocabulary is around ...</description><link>blog.ehudadler.com/posts/word-count</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 22:09:00 -0500</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Janurary 17th 2020</h1><p>Over the weekend I had a discussion with my friend and his family. How many words (english words that is) on average does a person know? We made some guesses. Some said ~1,000 (me, spoiler: way off), some 1 in every 2 words (which comes out to ~85,000 [1] )</p><p>We tried to approach the problem academically so we brought out a dictionary and started testing theories. First we estimated how many words were in the dictionary by counting how many words were on a single random page and multiplying by the number of pages in the book. Then we started picking random words and seeing how many people know what they meant. We were pretty lax about keeping track but I think we averaged around 1/3 (disclaimer: I am not counting proper nouns here). Finally we decided to look up the answer and so I can say,</p><p>Today I learned the following from the internet,</p><p>The average person, (based on a study conducted by the encomist in 2013), knows somewhere between 20k-35k words[1].</p><p>[1] https://wordcounter.io/blog/how-many-words-does-the-average-person-know/</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">blog.ehudadler.com/posts/orbit-area</guid><title>Janurary 16th 2020</title><description>The region between equally spaced moments in orbit always have the same area</description><link>blog.ehudadler.com/posts/orbit-area</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 22:09:00 -0500</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Janurary 16th 2020</h1><p>I am fortunate to be close with a few of the professors at my university. Recently one of them told me to watch a set of lectures known as the messengers lectures given by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Feynman">Richard Feynman</a>. Today I watched the first of these lectures (of which there are 7). The first lecture, titled "Law of Gravitation — An Example of Physical Law" can be found <a href="Law of Gravitation — An Example of Physical Law">on microsoft's website here</a> or on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j3mhkYbznBk&list=PLLzGzdSNup63lMYeOpU9Hax6MBsTjdDas">youtube here</a>.</p><p>So without further introduction.....</p><p>Today I learned the following fact from Richard Feynman.</p><h3>Keplers 2nd Law</h3><p>If you look at the area formed when you draw a line between the sun, some planet and that same planet 3 weeks later on in its orbit, the area formed by the enclosing region will <strong>always</strong> be the same. This means, no matter where in the orbit the planet is, the region formed between the sun and it now and it in 3 weeks will always be the same, Furthermore, there is nothing special about 3 weeks. As long as you look at equal intervals of time, the area will be the same. This concept is depicted in the image below where 1 month in the chosen interval.</p><img width=25% src="https://eloisechen.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/kepler2law.jpg?w=1600&h=1200">


]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>